{"1": {"question": "What was the lied heavily influenced by?", "correct": "Poetry", "incorrect": ["Lead", "The peppa pig theme song", "Musicals"]}, "2": {"question": "When was the lied a very significant part of music?", "correct": "In the 18th and 19th Century", "incorrect": ["20th Century", "17th Century", "2013"]}, "3": {"question": "How many lieder did Schubert write?", "correct": "Over 600", "incorrect": ["212", "Over 800", "413"]}, "4": {"question": "In lieder and art song, when are the poems (words) written?", "correct": "Before the music is written", "incorrect": ["Whenever the poet feels like it", "After the music is written", "At the same time as the music"]}, "5": {"question": "In lieder and art song, the piano accompaniment is of what as the vocal line?", "correct": "Equal importance", "incorrect": ["Less importance", "More importance", "Nothing"]}, "6": {"question": "In lieder and art song, what does the piano part attempt to do?", "correct": "Describe what is happening in the poem", "incorrect": ["Add rhythmic interest", "Make the piano part sound strange", "Add melodic interest"]}, "7": {"question": "What is the German word for 'song'?", "correct": "Lieder", "incorrect": ["Sung", "Chanson", "Canzone"]}, "8": {"question": "What instrumentation is art song written for?", "correct": "Solo voice and piano", "incorrect": ["2 Violins, Viola and Cello", "Solo Voice", "Piano"]}, "9": {"question": "Which of the following forms is often used in lied and art song?", "correct": "Modified Strophic Form", "incorrect": ["Through composed form", "Sonata Form", "Ternary form"]}, "10": {"question": "Which form consists of repeated sections of the music that are varied or elaborated forms of the basic theme?", "correct": "Modified Strophic Form", "incorrect": ["Binary Form", "Strophic Form", "Rondo Form"]}, "11": {"question": "Which form has new music in each stanza?", "correct": "Through-composed form", "incorrect": ["Strophic Form", "Ternary form", "Through composed form"]}, "12": {"question": "What is the smallest to largest instrument in the orchestral string family?", "correct": "Violin, Viola, Cello, Double Bass", "incorrect": ["Viola, Violin, Cello, Double Bass", "Double Bass, Cello, Viola, Violin", "Cello, Violin, Double Bass, Viola"]}, "13": {"question": "What is a colloquial name for the violin?", "correct": "The fiddle", "incorrect": ["Licorice Stick", "Thermometer", "Box"]}, "14": {"question": "How much lower is the viola tuned than the violin?", "correct": "A fifth", "incorrect": ["A fourth", "A sixth", "A third"]}, "15": {"question": "Which clef does the viola primarily use?", "correct": "The alto clef", "incorrect": ["The tenor clef", "The treble clef", "The bass clef"]}, "16": {"question": "What are the 3 clefs that the cello uses?", "correct": "Treble, tenor and bass", "incorrect": ["Alto, tenor and Bass", "Treble, alto and Bass", "Treble, Alto and tenor"]}, "17": {"question": "Which is the only stringed instrument that is tuned in fourths?", "correct": "The Double Bass", "incorrect": ["The viola", "The guitar", "The violin"]}, "18": {"question": "How much lower does the Double Bass sound compared to music written for it?", "correct": "An octave", "incorrect": ["A fifth", "A fourth", "A sixth"]}, "19": {"question": "Which clef does the violin use?", "correct": "Treble", "incorrect": ["Alto", "Bass", "Tenor"]}, "20": {"question": "Which clef does the Double Bass use?", "correct": "Bass clef", "incorrect": ["Tenor Clef", "Alto Clef", "It uses both the tenor and bass clef"]}, "21": {"question": "What sort of place would 18th-century chamber music be played in?", "correct": "A small venue", "incorrect": ["A large concert hall", "Anywhere", "A garage"]}, "22": {"question": "How many players are there usually per part in chamber music?", "correct": "One", "incorrect": ["None", "Three", "Two"]}, "23": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the key of the first movement?", "correct": "Tonic", "incorrect": ["Dominant", "Supertonic", "Mediant"]}, "24": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the key of the second movement?", "correct": "Subdominant", "incorrect": ["Submediant", "Leading-note", "Tonic"]}, "25": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the key of the third movement?", "correct": "Tonic", "incorrect": ["Subdominant", "Dominant", "Supertonic"]}, "26": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the key of the fourth movement?", "correct": "Tonic", "incorrect": ["Leading-note", "Submediant", "Mediant"]}, "27": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the form of the first movement?", "correct": "Sonata Form", "incorrect": ["Minuet and Trio", "Ternary form", "Strophic Form"]}, "28": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the form of the second movement?", "correct": "Ternary form", "incorrect": ["Modified Stropic form", "Rondo Form", "Binary Form"]}, "29": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the form of the third movement?", "correct": "Minuet and Trio", "incorrect": ["Binary Form", "Through-composed form", "Sonata Form"]}, "30": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the form of the fourth movement?", "correct": "Sonata Form", "incorrect": ["Rondo Form", "Modified Strophic Form", "Ternary form"]}, "31": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the speed/tempo of the first movement?", "correct": "Allegro", "incorrect": ["Slow", "Moderate", "Very Fast"]}, "32": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the speed/tempo of the second movement?", "correct": "Slow", "incorrect": ["Allegro", "Very Fast", "Moderate"]}, "33": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the speed/tempo of the third movement?", "correct": "Moderate", "incorrect": ["Very Fast", "Allegro", "Slow"]}, "34": {"question": "In the typical movement structure of a String Quartet by Haydn or Mozart, what is the speed/tempo of the fourth movement?", "correct": "Very Fast", "incorrect": ["Moderate", "Slow", "Allegro"]}, "35": {"question": "What is the cello's full name?", "correct": "Violoncello", "incorrect": ["The full name of a cello", "Violincello", "Violacello"]}, "36": {"question": "What is a mute?", "correct": "A device attached to an instrument to change the tone of it or to reduce its volume", "incorrect": ["A button on a conferencing software which disables the microphone", "A device attached to an instrument to stop all sound that comes from it", "A device attached to an instrument while tuning which shows whether the instrument is sharp or flat"]}, "37": {"question": "What is it meant by 'col legno'?", "correct": "An instruction for string players to strike a string with the stick part of the bow", "incorrect": ["An instruction for string players to pluck the strings", "Cool Lego", "Quick and Lively"]}, "38": {"question": "'Pizzicato' is the musical term for what?", "correct": "Plucking the strings", "incorrect": ["With spirit", "Extremely fast staccato playing", "An instruction for string players to strike a string with the stick part of the bow"]}, "39": {"question": "What does 'Con Sordino' mean?", "correct": "To play with the mute", "incorrect": ["Without", "Pluck the strings", "Eat Sardines"]}, "40": {"question": "What is a peg on a stringed instrument used for?", "correct": "To tighten or loosen the string while tuning", "incorrect": ["To change the tone of the instrument", "To make a string thinner", "To reduce the volume of the instrument"]}, "41": {"question": "'Arco' is the Italian term for what?", "correct": "To play with the bow", "incorrect": ["To play on or near the bridge", "To play with the stick part of the bow", "Slow; leisurely"]}, "42": {"question": "What does 'Spiccato' mean?", "correct": "Extremely fast staccato playing", "incorrect": ["Extremely slow staccato playing", "Short and accented staccato", "Slackening speed"]}, "43": {"question": "What does 'Sul Ponticello' mean?", "correct": "To play on or near the bridge", "incorrect": ["Pluck the strings", "Play with a cello", "To play with the bow"]}, "44": {"question": "What is the rule for melodic minor scales?", "correct": "The 6th and 7th scale degrees are raised on the way up, and both are lowered on the way down", "incorrect": ["Raise the 7th scale degree on the way up, and lower it on the way down", "The 6th and 7th scale degrees are lowered on the way up, and both are raised on the way down", "Raise the 6th scale degree on the way up, and lower it on the way down"]}, "45": {"question": "When writing a lied, when should a minor key be used?", "correct": "When the topic of the poem is sad", "incorrect": ["When the topic of the poem is happy", "If the poem is about free food", "When the poem is in third-person"]}, "46": {"question": "In first inversion chords, which degree of the chord is held in the bass part?", "correct": "The third", "incorrect": ["The tonic", "The fifth", "The eighth"]}, "47": {"question": "In 4 part vocal arrangements, how far apart can the tenor and bass voices be?", "correct": "As far apart as they like, but they must stay within vocal range", "incorrect": ["An octave", "A 7th", "Two octaves"]}, "48": {"question": "In 4 part vocal arrangements, how far apart can the soprano and alto be?", "correct": "An octave", "incorrect": ["A 3rd", "As far apart as they like, but they must stay within vocal range", "A 6th"]}, "49": {"question": "In 4 part vocal arrangements, how far apart can the alto and tenor be?", "correct": "An octave", "incorrect": ["A fourth", "A fifth", "As far apart as they like, but they must stay within vocal range"]}, "50": {"question": "Which note is doubled in first inversion chords?", "correct": "The tonic", "incorrect": ["The fifth", "The third", "No note is doubled"]}, "51": {"question": "Which sort of beat should a I64 chord land on?", "correct": "Strong beat", "incorrect": ["Weak beat", "The second beat", "The off-beat"]}, "52": {"question": "Which note is doubled in I64 chords?", "correct": "The fifth", "incorrect": ["The tonic", "The second", "The third"]}, "53": {"question": "Which chord must follow a I64 chord?", "correct": "Chord V", "incorrect": ["Chord ii", "Chord I", "Chord vi"]}, "54": {"question": "In the tenor part of a I64 chord, what does the tonic go to?", "correct": "The leading note", "incorrect": ["The dominant", "The supertonic", "The third"]}, "55": {"question": "Which chord must V6 lead to?", "correct": "Chord I", "incorrect": ["Chord V", "Chord vii", "Chord IV"]}, "56": {"question": "In two-part writing, scale degree no. 3 will always represent which chord?", "correct": "I6", "incorrect": ["V", "IV", "vi"]}, "57": {"question": "In two-part writing, scale degree no. 5 will always represent which chord?", "correct": "V", "incorrect": ["IV", "ii", "ii6"]}, "58": {"question": "In two-part writing, if the 3rd of the chord is in the bass, which note should we try to use in the treble?", "correct": "The root", "incorrect": ["The fifth", "The seventh", "The third"]}}